Elixir a dynamic general purpose programming language designed to build
Elixir 是一种动态通用编程语言，旨在
scalable concurrent applications with a beautiful functional syntax it was
使用优美的函数式语法构建
created by Jose velim and first released in 2012 and today it consistently ranks
among the most loved programming languages it runs on top of the erlang
beam virtual machine which itself is developed in the 1980s to scale the
可扩展的并发应用程序 它本身是在 1980 年代开发的，以扩展
massive demands of phone switching which it did with extreme reliability and bolt
电话切换的大量需求，它具有极高的可靠性和螺栓
tolerance Elixir was created to make this powerful technology accessible to
耐受性 Elixir 的创建是为了
the modern developer it's dynamically typed with a minimal ruby-inspired
使现代开发人员可以使用
syntax making it more approachable than statically type functional languages
这项强大的技术 比 Haskell 等静态类型的函数式语言
like Haskell however because it's compiled to beam by code it delivers
更容易接近，但是因为它是按代码编译的，所以与 Discord 等公司使用的解释性语言相比，它提供了
better performance and scalability compared to interpreted languages it's
更好的性能和可扩展性，它
used by companies like Discord to handle massive amounts of concurrent users by
被摩托罗拉用来处理大量并发用户，
Motorola to build fault tolerant communication systems by Pinterest to
以构建Pinterest 的容错通信系统 o
scale up their real-time notification system and The Elixir based Phoenix
扩展他们的实时通知系统和基于 Elixir 的 Phoenix
framework is responsible for thousands of full stack web applications to get
框架负责数以千计的全栈 Web 应用程序
started install erlang Andy Lex mixer then create a file ending in dot EXs to
开始安装 erlang Andy Lex 混合器然后创建一个以点 EXs 结尾的文件来
create a variable give it a name followed by a value it's Dynamic so no
创建一个变量，给它一个名称，然后 一个值，它是动态的，所以
type annotations are necessary now print it to the standard output with i o puts
不需要类型注释现在用 i o puts 将它打印到标准输出
and like Ruby parentheses are usually optional alternatively you might create
，就像 Ruby 括号通常是可选的，或者你可以创建
an atom which is a constant whose value is its own name Anonymous functions can
一个原子，它是一个常量，其值是它自己的名字匿名函数可以
be created with the FN keyword which can then be assigned to variables or passed
用 FN 关键字，然后可以分配给变量或
around to other functions and you can even simplify this expression further
传递给其他函数，您甚至可以在使用函数表达式
using the Ampersand shorthand when working with function Expressions you
时使用与符号简写进一步简化此表达式，您
can use the pipe operator to pass the value of one expression to another
可以使用管道运算符将一个表达式的值传递给另一个表达式，
without the need for a deeply nested function calls create a list of items
而无需 对于深度嵌套的函数调用，创建一个带括号的项目列表
with brackets or create a map to represent key value pairs the equal sign
或创建一个映射来表示键值 p 等号
can be used to assign variables but it's actually called the match operator to
可用于分配变量，但它实际上称为匹配运算符以
support pattern matching features for example we might destructure a list into
支持模式匹配功能，例如，如果模式不匹配，我们可能会将列表解构为
a set of variables if a pattern doesn't match it will raise an error and this
一组变量，它将引发错误，并且此
Behavior can be used to implement Advanced control flow logic if and its
行为可以 用于实现高级控制流逻辑 if 及其
inverse and less can be used for basic situations but the case keyword allow
逆和 less 可用于基本情况，但 case 关键字
allows us to compare a value against many patterns until we find a matching
允许我们将一个值与许多模式进行比较，直到找到匹配的
one application code can be organized and shared with modules inside a module
一个应用程序代码可以组织并与内部模块共享 一个
we can Define multiple functions but one of the killer features of this language
我们可以定义多个函数的模块，但是这种语言的杀手级特性之一
is its concurrency model thanks to the erlang VM all code runs in processes
是它的并发模型，这要归功于erlang VM 所有代码都在彼此隔离的进程中运行，这些进程
that are isolated from each other which communicate by passing messages they are
通过传递消息进行通信，它们
extremely lightweight and your application can run thousands of them
非常轻量级，您的应用程序可以运行 数千个它们
simultaneously resulting in high performance fault tolerant execution
同时导致高性能容错执行
this has been elixir in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like
如果这在 100 秒内是灵丹妙药想看更多
this hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and I will see you
像这样的短视频点击点赞订阅感谢收看我们下期再见
in the next one